在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
你们三个最好接受我们的监护
It is best that you three remain under our watch.
“将得黑暗能量”！
Gaze upon Dark Dnergon.
传说它威力无比 甚至能…起死回生
Legend tells that it holds the power to... revive the dead.
飞过山的信号又出现了
Cliffjumper's signal pop back online.
我们去找飞过山
Let's find Cliffjumper.
飞过山！
Cliff!
这是什么？
What is this?
不知道 飞过山浑身上下都是这东西
Don't know. Cliff was covered in it.
等等！威震天陛下！
Wait! Lord Megatron
您不知道会有什么后果！
you do not know what it will do!
抓紧了 杰克
Tighten your grip, Jack.
你这是怎么了 阿尔茜？
Heh... Hey, what's with you, Arcee?
如果没有人追杀 你可能会感觉好一点
Thought you might actually enjoy the ride if you weren't getting shot at.
噢 那就来吧！
Oh, bring it!
准备好了？开始！
Ready? Set...
神子 我的职责是保护你
Miko, I'm supposed to be protecting you.
隔板 我待在十吨重的钢筋铁骨里面
Bulkhead, I'm strapped tight inside ten tons of metal muscle.
万无一失
I'm protected.
不公平 大黄蜂
No fair, Bumblebee
你的驾龄比我长多了
you've been driving a lot longer than I have.
总算安静下来了
Thank goodness for peace and quiet.
我们的客人还真难缠
House guests can be such a bother.
这是？
What?
擎天柱？
Optimus?
我的火种源啊！
Oh, by the Allspark!
那个我还有用呐！
I needed that!
别想翻身！
Stay broken!
那东西是什么来头？
Now, what could have caused that?!
我有个不详的预感 救护车
I have a grave suspicion, Ratchet.
黑暗能量
Dark Energon.
威震天陛下
Uh... haha, Lord Megatron?
“破坏者”宇宙大帝之血
It's as if the blood of Unicron the Destroyer
好像流遍了我浑身的经脉
flows through my veins.
我好像感受到他的思想了
As if I hear his very thoughts.
我现在知道该怎么做了
I now know what I must do.
那我要怎样效劳呢 主人？
Ugha, haha... And what can I do to assist you, master?
别装可怜
Quit grovelling
等我发令吧！
and wait my command!
声波！
Soundwave!
我怀疑 我们的主人去摘星的时候
I fear that when our master reached for the stars
感染上了某种…太空疯狂症
he came down with a touch of... space madness.
威震天陛下自从回归后 一直没有做出正确的判断
Lord Megatron has not been having sound judgement since his return.
加强全球监控！
Increase global surveillance!
“别装可怜”
"Quit grovelling
“等我发令吧！”
and wait my command!"
我不是聋子！
I'm not deaf!
但如果擎天柱真的还活着
But if Optimus Prime lives
我相信 如果我们能把他干掉
I believe it is in Lord Megatron's best interest
威震天陛下会龙颜大悦的
that we insure his enemy's destruction.
如果阿尔茜从飞过山身上取得的残留物
If the residual Arcee found on Cliffjumper
能让损坏的器材复活
brought you a broken equipment to life
那就是说 同样的物质也能让飞过山起死回生
it would stand a reason that the very same substance brought Cliffjumper back from the dead.
他的生命信号突然出现 也能说得通了
That would account for his life signal inexplicably coming back online
可是…那会是黑暗能量吗？
but Dark Energon?
那东西非常罕见 几乎搜索不到
It's so scarce as to be virtually non-existent.
它怎么会在地球上出现呢？
What would it be doing on earth?
它是被威震天带来的
It was transported by Megatron.
他目的何在？
For what purpose?
召集一支不死大军
To conquer this planet
征服这个星球
by raising an army of the undead.
这么说 威震天需要无数个旧烤箱了
Uh heh... Well, Megatron will need to break quite a few toaster ovens
我是说 在这个星球上
I mean, where on this world
哪有那么多塞博特恩星人的尸体啊？
would he find that many Cybertronian dead?
帅呆了
That was awesome.
我们能再玩儿一次吗？
Can we go again?
爽啊！
S-weet!
对不起
Sorry
一定是我丢在后座上的
must have left that in the backseat.
汽车人 准备…
Autobots, prepare to...
出发？
Roll out?
坚守岗位
Remain here.
救护车 跟我来
Ratchet, you'll come with me.
阿尔茜 我们会暂时中断联络信号
Arcee, we'll be outside communications range for some time.
你来接管基地
So I'm putting you in charge.
哥们儿 你个头最大
Dude, you're biggest.
你该当老大
You should be the boss.
呃 他…从不选我
Umm, he... never picks me.
擎天柱 恕我直言
Optimus, with all due respect
做保镖是一回事 看孩子是另一回事
playing bodyguard is one thing, baby-sitting is another.
还有 战后救护车根本没出过基地
Besides, Ratchet hasn't been in the field since the war.
我的活塞可能有点生锈
My pistons might be rusty
但我听得很清楚
but my hearing is sharp as ever.
这次嘛 只是侦察
For the moment, it's only reconnaissance.
那你的声音怎么有点不安？
Then why do I hear an edge in your voice?
阿尔茜 过去的24小时里发生了很多变化
Arcee, much has changed in the last 24 hours.
我们都需要去适应
And we all need to adapt.
救护车 把我们传送走
Ratchet, bridge us out.
好的 老大 那…
Okay, chief, so...
有什么活动？
what's on the activities list?
我去巡逻
I'm going on patrol.
但大哥叫我们呆在这里
But Optimus told us to stay.
你当头儿时 你就说了算
When you're in charge, you can call the shots.
小蜂 跟我来
Bee, with me.
隔板 你来当家
Bulkhead, you're in charge.
那…有什么活动？
So, eh... what's on the activities list?
我们来…乐队排练吧！
How about... band practice?!
可我们不是乐手啊
But we're not a band.
别这么不近人情 来吧 拉夫
Why so ambisocial? Come on, Raf
你带了什么？
you play anything?
键盘行吗？
Umm... keyboard?
电脑套装 很好 杰克？
Laptop ensembles, good. Jack?
我…只是有时候玩玩口琴
I... sometimes mess around on the harmonica.
我像玩乡村音乐的吗？
Do I look like I do country?
往身上涂些假血
Just cover yourself in fake blood
然后边跳边尖叫
and jump around screaming.
隔板 注意
Bulkhead, precaution.
重型音效来了
Look over big industrial sound.
自力更生 乐队组成
DIY, we're a band.
你们最好学学那些歌
You just got to learn the songs.
这首是民谣
This one is a ballad.
《我的拳你的脸》（史密斯飞船乐队）
"My fist your face"
不是吧 你受不了这种原生力量？
Come on, you can't handle the raw power?
近程传感器 快藏起来！
Proximity sensor. Quick, hide!
擎天柱！
Prime!
福勒探员 呃 大哥不在
Agent Fowler, ugh, he's not here.
这儿没有人
Nobody's here.
除了我以外
Except me, of course.
那他去哪儿了？
Well, where did he go?
等等 别告诉我 他在糟蹋一个小商场
Wait, don't tell me. He's out pancaking a mini mall.
我不管你们汽车人在自己的星球上说什么语言
Now, I don't know what language your bots speak on your planet
但擎天柱承诺过 你们会搞定霸天虎
but Prime promised you will handle the Decepticons.
在内布拉斯加州炸出个大弹坑
And blowing a crater in the middle of Nebraska
可不是“搞定”的意思
is not what the word "handle" means in English.
你给我告诉擎天柱…
So you tell Prime...
你们什么时候开始用电驱动了？
Since when do you bots electric?
嘿 你好吗？
Hey, how are you doing?
有生人介入
Contact with civilians.
领袖卫队这次太不像话了
Team Prime has really gone off book this time.
等等 别告诉我你们在办托儿所吗？
Wait, don't tell me. You're running a day-care center?
好吧…
Okay...
我们是…实习生
Uh, we're... interns.
在校实习生
Student interns.
要赚外快去买汽车
Earning extra credit in the auto shop.
买机器人
Robotics.
好 我们走
Ok. Let's move.
我会把你们三个带到联邦拘留所
I'm taking all three of you to federal custody.
为了你们的自身安全
That's for your own protection.
他们的安全由我们保护
We're protecting them.
真的吗？
Is that so?
那你可以向我在五角大楼的上司们解释
Well, maybe you can explain that to my superiors at the Pentagon.
别用那个电话 它…
Don't use that phone, it's...
坏了
out of order.
这不算完 大脚 走着瞧
This isn't over, big foot. Not by a long shot.
擎天柱 我们来这儿要找什么？
Optimus, what do we hope to find here?
这是塞博特恩战争在银河系中最大的战场
The site of the largest Cybertronian battlefield in this galaxy.
在地球上？
On Earth?
你在开玩笑吧！
You must be joking!
你还记得战争的末期吗？
Do you recall the period late in the war
双方都把找到的能量藏在外星球
when both sides began hiding their energon spoils off world?
当然记得 所以在这样的星球上会有能量矿
Of course, it's the reason energon deposits exist on planet such as this one.
正是如此 这样的星球上才会有战争
It is also the reason battles came to be waged on planet such as this one.
我担心 威震天会知道一些很久远的事情
And I fear Megatron's memory is as long as history.
长官 我是福勒探员
Sir, Agent Fowler.
有情况
We have a situation.
我刚从汽车人基地出来
I'm in route from the Autobot base.
我会亲自向您汇报
I'll brief you in person.
“我是福勒探员”
"Agent Fowler."
“我刚从汽车人基地出来”
"I'm in route from the Autobot base."
“我会亲自向您汇报”
"I'll brief you in person."
汽车人基地啊…
Autobot base...
人类永远是弱点所在
human's always the weak link.
把这个福勒给我带来
Fetch me this Fowler
让他给我们做个汇报
so that he may brief us instead.
嘿 大鸟 别打扰我开飞机
Hey, big bird, I'm flying here.
这是什么鬼东西？
What in Uncle Sam's beard?
先是高速公路不安全
First, the freeways aren't safe
现在轮到天上了？
now air travel?
你想跳舞吗 虎子？
You wanna dance, Con?
我来领舞！
I'll lead!
真正需要汽车人的时候 没一个靠谱的
Never an Autobot around when you actually need one.
我的耳朵！
My ears!
是求救信号
It's an SOS
福勒发的
from Fowler.
你追踪到了吗？
Did you trace it?
方位扫描无法完成
Location scan wasn't complete.
管他呢
Oh, well.
“管他呢”？
"Oh, well"
不是吧？
seriously?
福勒是个混蛋
Fowler's a jerk.
先别说他坏话 霸天虎可能把他抓住了
Wow! Whether you like the guy or not, the Decepticons may have him.
福勒探员知道你们的位置…
And Agent Fowler knows your location...
我们的位置
mm... our location.
我们刚才也看见了 福勒在他们面前毫无还手之力
And did we not just witness how fast Fowler backs down from a bot?
虎子们肯定会给他用酷刑的
The Cons will totally make him squeal.
可我们失去联系了
But we lost the transmission.
福勒有可能在任何地方
Fowler could be anywhere.
我或许能把范围缩小
Maybe I can narrow it down.
大约五年前 政府开始在探员身上植入晶片
About five years ago, the government started micro-chipping their agents.
就像主人对待宠物一样
You know, like owners do with pets.
怎么了？我在电视上见过
What? I saw it on TV.
总之 如果我能入侵联邦政府的主机
Anyway, if I can hack into the Fed's main frame
就可能找到福勒的坐标
maybe I can pinpoint Fowler's coordinates.
你还是黑客呐？
You know how to hack?
可你才…两岁啊
But you're like... two years old.
十二岁…零三个月
Twelve, and a quarter.
欢迎你
Welcome
福勒探员
Agent Fowler.
你对所有客人都这么友好吗？
Uh, you treat all your guests this nice?
特别是对汽车人的朋友
Hmhmhmm... Any friend of the Autobots.
汽车人？
Autobot?
那些投币式的洗车机器？
That one of them coin-operated
"wash my own car" places?
噢 原来你吃硬不吃软
Oh, so that's how it's going to be?
看来没人告诉过你 我不喜欢人类的幽默感
Apparently, no one has told you I have no appreciation for human humor.
好好招待我们的客人
Make our guest comfortable.
北纬39.5°西经116.9°
Latitude 39.5°, longitude 116.9°.
好 在这儿等着
Ok, wait here.
噢 乐队不能散啊！
Oh, don't break up the band!
呃 杰克 你来当家
Ugh, Jack, you're in charge.
看来我们三个可以为所欲为了
Guess we three have the run of the place.
神子？
Miko?
福勒？
Fowler?
一整窝的霸天虎
The whole Decepticon ship-bay.
好了
Alright
有什么计划？
what's the plan?
神子！
Miko!
噢 搞砸了
Oh, unwise.
神子 趴下！
Miko, get down!
把他按住！
Hold him still!
神子 别看！
Miko, look away!
- 但…\N- 把头扭过去！
But...
阿尔茜 大黄蜂 你们收到了吗？
Arcee, Bumblebee, do you read?
很清楚 隔板
Loud and clear, Bulkhead.
我这儿有点情况
I have a situation.
隔板 他们是孩子
Bulkhead, they're children
是人类 随便点
humans. Just do whatever.
你在哪儿？
You're where?
她在哪儿？
She's where?!
我们怎么办？
What should we do?
隔板可能还不知道 她也去了
Bulkhead may not even realize that she followed him.
神子和我们不一样 她没见过虎子的行动
Miko hasn't seen the Cons in action like we have.
她一无所知
She has no idea.
坐标还锁定在他们的目的地
Those are the coordinates
their destination still locked in.
呃 你来当家
Umm, you're in charge.
当谁的家？
In charge of who?
阿尔茜呼叫基地 回话
Arcee to base, come in.
杰克 听着 你得把我们传送回去
Jack? Listen up, we need you to bridge us back.
喂？
Hello?
大黄蜂 全速出发
Bumblebee, metal to the pedal.
福勒探员 我有一个简单的请求
Agent Fowler, I have one simple request
可以让你的家人免遭痛苦
that will save your family the pain of grieving.
告诉我汽车人基地的位置
Tell me the location of the Autobot base.
没问题
No problem.
但我先要问问你
But I need to ask you something first.
说吧 我听着呢
Yes, I'm listening.
我对这里的客户服务不太满意
I got an issue with the customer service around here.
我可以跟经理谈谈吗？
Could I speak to the manager?
我说的话就是圣旨
I make the decisions here.
这儿我说了算！
I am in charge!!
把能量棍拿来
Bring the prod.
阿尔茜和大黄蜂怎么还没来？
What's taking Arcee and Bumblebee?
哥们儿 虎子可能正给福勒上大刑呢
Dude, the Cons could be putting the clamps on Fowler right now.
我们干脆冲过去得了
Let's just storm the joint.
他们来了
Uhh, they're here.
他们怎么不跟自己的搭档玩儿？
Why don't those guys hang with their own bots?
现在是我们的二人世界
This is our one-on-one time.
你骨头还在颤吗？
Whoaa... are your bones vibrating?
你们俩！
You there!
- 糟了\N- 糟了
- Scrap.\N- Scrap.
我再客气地问你最后一次
I ask nicely one last time:
汽车人基地在哪儿？
the Autobot base!
没问题 老兄
Sure thing, buddy.
可你得先吃掉我的小星星短裤！
Right after you eat my star spangle shorts!
跟我想的一样
As I imagined
能量和人类神经系统相互排斥
energon and human nerval systems don't mix.
擎天柱 我这辈子第一次希望你是错的
For the first time in my life, Optimus, I had hoped that you were wrong.
擎天柱 你还好吗？
Optimus, been well?
你把那条忠心的看门狗也带来了
I see you brought your trusty watchdog.
我还以为他在废料场里养老呢
I will certainly be convalesce in the scrapyard by now.
你干嘛不叫他下来谈谈呢？
Why don't you invite him down here for a chat?
我知道你为什么来这里 威震天
I know why you're here, Megatron.
这难不住你 擎天柱
Hardly a surprise, Optimus.
毕竟 我们已经相处这么久了
After all, you and I have been at this a long time.
而你的大限快要到了
And your time has come to an end.
觉醒吧 我的战士们！
Rise, my army!
我的火种源啊！
By the Allspark!
请看 这就是传说中的…黑暗能量！
Behold, the power of Dark Energon!